Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 15.
We are asked to find the time complexity of this sequence Fibonacci sequence, and it is enlisted as
a method.
We are going to see this recursive functions and the recursive concept in the next videos.
So don't worry if you don't understand the exercise 15 or 14, we're going to clarify everything later
on.
But for for understanding and covering all the way and all that algorithm, algorithmic notations and
big annotations, we are going to obligatory put Fibonacci and factorial and recursive inside these
exercises in order to cover all the possibilities.
And if the big old notation OK to be a reference for you if you need to revise anything or review anything.
OK.
Both the video and think about this.
OK, so let's begin and Fibonacci and and if any less than or equal to zero return zero, this would
be executed as oh of one else if an equal equal to one return zero one.
So it this of one.
Return Fibonacci and minus one plus Fibonacci and minus two.
We are going to call recursively the function again here, but here we are passing and minus one at
the first time.
And plus Fibonacci and minus two and the second time.
OK, so let's take an example to better understand this.
I will take an equal to five.
OK.
Let's calculate the Fibonacci number of an equal to five.
Fibonacci, it is it's a series that calculates the number, the previous number and by previous two
numbers, add them together.
So five.
It is less than or equal to zero, no equal, equal to one, no.
It will return Fibonacci.
So the first calling of this function would be a return.
Fibonacci of mine and minus one, it will call FIB of four.
OK, plus.
We are going to see this later, OK?
So Fibonacci of four, Fibonacci of four.
Is equal to Fibonacci of three, plus Fibonacci of two.
But this would be.
This would be executed at first.
So Fibonacci of three is equal to Fibonacci of two plus Fibonacci of one.
OK.
And Fibonacci of two.
Fibonacci of two equals nature of one, plus Fibonacci of C.
Here.
Fibonacci of one.
If an equal equal to one return, one self of one is equal to one plus people net of zero returns.
OK, so the Fibonacci of two is equal to zero to one here, one plus zero equal to one.
So go and substitute.
And the previous method or the previous call.
F f to f of two equal one.
So I will remove to put inside to.
Substitute two by one and f of one is equal to one and to return one.
So f of one is equal to one.
So one plus one is equal to three.
So Fibonacci of three is going to be executed above and would be substituted by two and Fibonacci of
two.
Would be equal to Fibonacci of one plus Fibonacci two.
It is equal to one.
We have calculated it before.
OK.
So f of two is gone and f of three is equal to two.
So after four is two plus one is equal to three.
So Fibonacci of two of four is equal to three.
Now, let's continue Fibonacci of four plus Fibonacci of three and Fibonacci of three is equal.
F of two plus f of one.
OK, f of two.
Here is equal f of one plus f of zero and f of one is equal to one.
OK.
F of one is one and f of zero is zero, so f of two is equal to one.
One plus one is equal to do so.
F of the three Fibonacci of three is equal to two.
Therefore, there should be a net of five is equal to five.
OK.
We have two branches per call, and we go as deep as.
So therefore, the runtime on there of this complexity, this algorithm would be two to power and through
some very complicated math, we can actually get a tie to run time.
That time is indeed exponential, but it is actual actually closer to oh of 1.6 power MN.
The Fibonacci series is one point power, and that isn't that is not exactly a two to power.
And is that at the bottom of the call stack?
There is some sometimes only the one call.
It turns out that a lot of the nodes are the at the bottom as in truth and most trees.
So in the sink, this single versus double call actually make a big difference, saying all of dude
power and would sufficient for the scope of an interview room through this would be a perfect square
answer because you might get a bonus point if you can recognize that it's actually less than that.
It is about one point six to power.
And OK, this is the Fibonacci see.
It is acting as 1.6 power and almost around this.
OK, but when you have a question in the interview, say Oh of two its power and.